Finding Aid for Joe O’Neal papers, 1912-1918 and 1969-1972
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Joe O’Neal papers 1912-1918 and 1969-1972
O’Neal, Joe
1 linear foot (in 2 boxes)
2009183 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Joe O’Neal (donor no. 10268 ) in October 2009.
Periodic additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Joe O'Neal is president of O'Neal Construction, an Ann Arbor, Michigan based general contractor and construction manager. The firm was established in 1961. Notable among the projects he had overseen is the building of the Power Center for the Performing Arts at the University of Michigan (project completed in 1971). Another is the construction of new gates and other repairs on the four dams on the Huron River in Ann Arbor. The project was completed in 1972.
The O'Neal collection consists of project files from the building of the Power Center for the Performing Arts on the University of Michigan campus and the construction of new gates and other repairs on the four dams on the Huron River in Ann Arbor, Michigan. The collection consists mainly of photographs detailing progress on each project, with some correspondence, construction documents, clippings, and dedication materials. The collection has been maintained in the order received from the donor. Some of the files include comments by the donor on the photographs and explaining the various stages of construction for each project.
Subjects:
Dams--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Huron River (Oakland County-Monroe County, Mich.); O'Neal, Joe.; Power Center for the Performing Arts.; Theaters--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan--Buildings.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Construction--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Dam construction--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Huron River (Oakland County-Monroe County, Mich.); O'Neal, Joe.; Power Center of the Performing Arts.; Theaters--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan--Buildings.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Project Files, (The folder headings were provided by the donor; the series consists largely of photographs.)
  - Power Center for the Performing Arts, 1969-1971
    (include some later publicity and retrospective articles)
    - Project Sign (photograph) (Box 1)
    - Notification of Award to O'Neal Construction (Box 1)
    - Site before Construction (Box 1)
    - Dale Fisher Aerial Photographs-From Start to Finish (Box 1)
    - Early Foundation Work-Stage Area (Box 1)
    - Main Front Concrete Columns (Box 1)
    - Proscenium Beam (Box 1)
    - Structural Steel Erection (Box 1)
    - Balthazar Korab Structural Steel Photographs (Box 1)
    - Auditorium and Balcony (Box 1)
    - Final Concrete Placement on Stage Tower (Box 1)
    - Temporary Access to Stage Tower Wall Forming Equipment and Permanent Spiral Stairway to Access Fly Gallery At Top of Stage (Box 1)
    - Concrete Spiral Stairs (Box 1)
    - Plaster Sound Clouds at Ceiling of Auditorium (Box 1)
    - Faces of the People That Built Power Center (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous Construction Photographs (Box 1)
    - Grand Opening (Box 1)
    - Exterior Photographs-Project Complete (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings (Box 1)
    - "University Record" Articles (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous Publications (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous Documents (Box 1)
    - O'Neal Construction; U.W. Stoll Marketing Pieces (Box 1)
    - "Scaffolding Wasn't Part of the Set" (Box 1)
    - OSU Football Program November 25, 1972 Labeling the Power Center for the Performing Arts as the Power Plant (Box 1)
    - UM Acceptance of Power Center; Miscellaneous Communications (Box 1)
  - Huron River Dams project
    - Working files, 1970-1972
      - Prior to Dam Project (1) (Box 1)
      - Barton Dam (2) (Box 1)
      - Argo Dam (3) (Box 1)
      - Geddes Dam (4) (Box 1)
      - Superior Dam (5) (Box 1)
      - Photos Taken at Time Project was Bid -- Before any Construction (6) (Box 1)
      - Dedication (7) (Box 1)
      - Progress Reports (8) (Box 1)
      - Newspaper Articles (9) (Box 1)
      - Gallup Park (10) (Box 1)
    - Original maps and plans, 1912-1918, photocopies
      - Map of the Argo Power Plant of the Eastern Michigan Edison Co. prepared by Gardner S. Williams, consulting engineer, 1912 (Box 2)
      - Plans for the Barton Plant of the Huron River Development designed for the Eastern Michigan Edison Company by Gardner S. Williams, consulting engineer, 1912 (Box 2)
      - Plans for the Geddes Plant of the Huron River Development designed for the Detroit Edison Company by Gardner S. Williams, consulting engineer, 1917 (Box 2)
      - Plans for the Superior Plant of the Huron River Development designed for the Detroit Edison Company by Gardner S. Williams, consulting engineer, 1918 (Box 2)